const quiz = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "How many stripes are there on the US flag?",
    ans: "13",
    options: ["13", "9", "12", "11"],
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "What’s the smallest country in the world?",
    ans: "The Vatican",
    options: ["Opatowiec", "The Vatican", "Vaduz", "San Marino"],
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question:
      "Norwegian artist Edvard Munch is famous for painting which iconic piece?",
    ans: "The Scream",
    options: ["The Scream", "Starry Night", "Puberty", "Madonna"],
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: "Which famous graffiti artist comes from Bristol?",
    ans: "Banksy",
    options: ["Lady Pink", "Jean-Michel Basquiat", "Keith Haring", "Banksy"],
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "Which artist painted the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel in Rome?",
    ans: "Michelangelo",
    options: [
      "Michelangelo",
      "Picasso",
      "Vincent van Gogh",
      "Leonardo da Vinci",
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: "When did they open the London underground?",
    ans: "1863",
    options: ["1863", "1850", "1870", "1899"],
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "How many keys does a classic piano have?",
    ans: "88",
    options: ["88", "90", "91", "85"],
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question:
      "Who is 3rd on the all-time list of female tennis Grand Slam champions?",
    ans: "Serena Williams",
    options: ["Serena Williams", "Mahak Jain", "steffi graf", "Ashleigh Barty"],
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: "How many breeds of elephant are there?",
    ans: "3",
    options: ["3", "2", "5", "none of the above"],
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: "How much screentime does Aurora from Sleeping Beauty have?",
    ans: "18min",
    options: ["18min", "60min", "25min", "43min"],
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question: "What year was Marmite invented?",
    ans: "1902",
    options: ["1902", "1800", "1907", "1891"],
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question: "How many letter tiles are there in a game of Scrabble?",
    ans: "100",
    options: ["100", "101", "105", "91"],
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question: "who won the first football World Cup and what year was it?",
    ans: "Uruguay in 1930",
    options: [
      "Uruguay in 1930",
      "Brazil in 1929",
      "Germany in 1925",
      "Argentina in 1927",
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question: "Who designed the Eiffel Tower?",
    ans: "Gustave Eiffel",
    options: [
      "Gustave Eiffel",
      "Jean Eiffel",
      "Margaux Eiffel",
      "Clémence Eiffel",
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question: "What month of which year was the first iPhone released?",
    ans: "June 2007, on the 29th",
    options: [
      "June 2007, on the 29th",
      "October 2006, on the 21st",
      "November 2008, on the 27th",
      "June 2007, on the 27th",
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    question: "Name the longest river in the UK",
    ans: "River Severn",
    options: ["River Severn", "River Thames", "River Trent", "River Trent"],
  },
];

export default quiz;
